# **Nate Lipp**

# **Full Stack Web Development**

1551 Larkin St, San Francisco, CA 94109 (415)-650-8042 nateplipp@gmail.com

Github https://github.com/Nalipp
Portfolio https://nalipp.github.io/portfolio

## SUMMARY

Experience working with JavaScript and Ruby full stack web applications

Three years of focused study, experimentation, and building web applications alone and on teams Active volunteer in the community including front-end instructor for LearnTeachCode Seoul Korea

# **PHILOSOPHY**

- Rock star without the ego
- Willing to put in the deliberate practice needed to get really good at a technology
- Fascinated with web app design patterns and principals
- Interested in improving app quality through testing and automation
- Desire to work with, learn from, and build up the people around me

#### COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

#### LEARN TEACH CODE SEOUL

Student and Instructor

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

- Helped over 100 students learn fundamentals of web development
- Lectured and led workshops on a weekly basis

#### **EDUCATION PROGRAMS**

LAUNCH SCHOOL Aug 2016 - April 2017

# JavaScript, Ruby, Minitest, Web Development, SQL, HTML, Sinatra, jQuery

- Completed both Backend and Frontend Tracks
- Self-paced curriculum requiring successful completion of written and oral exams

## **UDACITY NANODEGREE**

April 2016 - June 2016

# Ruby, OOP, Metaprogramming, RSpec

- Participated in peer code reviews and instructor led Skype sessions

## **SELF - EDUCATION**

## **PLURALSIGHT**

Building a JavaScript Development Environment

Introduction to Node.js

Building Web Applications with Node.js and Express 4.0

A Better CSS: LESS and SASS CSS Flexbox Fundamentals

#### LAUNCH SCHOOL

**Programming Foundations** 

Object Oriented Programming

Ruby Foundations: More Topics

Web Development

SQL and Relational Databases

HTML and CSS

Computational Thinking and JavaScript Programming

Front End Development with JavaScript

## UDEMY

The Complete Developers Guide to MongoDB

The Web Developer Bootcamp

Ultimate MySQL

The Complete Node.js Developer Course

The Professional Ruby on Rails Developer

The Complete Ruby on Rails Developer Course

Angular & NodeJS - The MEAN Stack Guide

#### **UDACITY**

Responsive Web Design Fundamentals

Object-Oriented JavaScript

JavaScript Basics

Intro to jQuery

HTML5 Canvas

Web Development

#### ALL ABOUT

#### Story

While living in Seoul, my partner and I developed a business connecting Korean students with teachers from the Philippines. We hacked together a company website but needed to automate some of the business processes. I began studying Python and soon after Ruby on Rails. The business faded but I stayed hooked on web development.

#### What I do

Practice a lot. Almost everyday, and have done so since I picked up the first Python book. I try to complete a cycle of learning a new concept, applying it to a project, and if possible teaching it either in the classroom or through pair programming.

# Why I love it

I see web development as a craft that takes a tremendous amount of effort. It feels like learning an instrument where deliberate practice results in better performance. But with web development you get to provide a more direct value to organizations and people.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **ENGLISH TEACHER IN SOUTH KOREA**

2010 - 2017

# Chugye University for the Arts Seoul, Uchon private Elementary, Jawoon Afterschool program

- Worked my way from a public school in a suburb to a highly coveted position in Seoul

#### **ENGLISH TEACHER AND ENTREPRENEUR**

2013 - 2017

## Nate and Julia - afterschool English program

- Co-founded an afterschool program that served over 40 local kids

#### Gaby - Skype English Lessons

- Created a service connecting adult Korean students with teachers from the Philippines

#### ADDITIONAL LEADERSHIP

# JONGO LANGUAGE EXCHANGE

2014 - 2017

# Original Co-organizer

- Founded a weekly study group that grew to over 3800 language learners
- Learned to listen more and talk less, and how to make others feel comfortable